Charles and Ray were a team. They were husband and wife.
تشارلز وراي كانوا فريقا. كانوا زوجا وزوجة.
Despite the New York Times' and Vanity Fair's best efforts recently,
على الرغم من أفضل الجهود لنيويورك تايمز وفانتي فير مؤخرا،
they're not brothers. (Laughter)
انهم ليسوا اخوة.
And they were a lot of fun.
وكانوا مسلّين جدا.
You know, Ray was the one who wore the ampersands in the family.
انتم تعرفون، راي كان الشخص الذي لبس العواطف في العائلة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We are going to focus on Charles today, because it is Charles' 100th birthday.
سوف نركز على تشارلز اليوم. لأنه عيد ميلاده المئة.
But when I speak of him, I'm really speaking of both of them as a team.
لكن عندما أتكلم عنه، أنا فعليا أتحدث عن كليهما كفريق.
Here's Charles when he was three. So he would be 100 this June.
ها هو تشارلز عندما كان في الثالثة. اذن سيبلغ ال 100 في يوليو المقبل.
We have a lot of cool celebrations that we're going to do.
لدينا الكثير من الاحتفالات التي سنقوم بها.
The thing about their work
المهم حول أعمالهم
is that most people come to the door of furniture --
أن معظم الناس تأتي من باب الأثاثات --
I suspect you probably recognize this chair
أفترض أنكم قد تعرفون هذا الكرسي
and some of the others I'm going to show you.
وبعض الكراسي الأخرى التي سأريكم اياها.
But we're going to first enter through the door of the Big Top.
لكننا سوف ندخل أولا خلال الباب الكبير.
The whole thing about this, though, is that, you know, why am I showing it?
الشيئ المجمل عن كل هذا، أنه، أنتم تعرفون، لماذا أعرضه؟
Is it because Charles and Ray made this film?
هل لأن تشارلز وراي صنعوا هذا الفيلم؟
This is actually a training film for a clown college that they had.
هذا في الحقيقة فيلم تدريبي لمهرّج كلية كان لديهم.
They also practiced a clown act when the future of furniture
أيضا هم تدربوا على دور مهرج عندما لم يكن مستقبل الأثاث
was not nearly as auspicious as it turned out to be.
مبشرا كما تحول ليكون.
There is a picture of Charles. So let's watch the next clip.
هناك صورة لتشارلز. اذا لنشاهد القطع التالي.
The film that we're about to see is a film they made for the Moscow World's Fair.
الفيلم الذي سنشاهده عملوه لمعرض موسكو العالمي .
Video: This is the land.
الفيديو: هذه هي الأرض.
It has many contrasts.
انها تحتوي العديد من التناقضات.
It is rough and it is flat.
انها خشنة و مستوية.
In places it is cold.
في أماكن انها باردة.
In some it is hot.
في اخرى انها حارة.
Too much rain falls on some areas,
الكثير من الأمطار يسقط في بعض المناطق.
and not enough on others.
وليس كافيا في أخرى.
But people live on this land.
لكن الناس يعيشون على هذه الأرض.
And, as in Russia,
و، كما في روسيا،
they are drawn together into towns and cities.
انهم ينجذبون معا الي القرى والمدن.
Here is something of the way they live.
هنا شيئ من الطريقة التي يعيشون بها.
Eames Demetrios: Now, this is a film that was hardly ever seen in the United States.
ايمز ديميتريوس: الآن، هذا فيلم كان من النادر مشاهدته في الولايات المتحدة.
It was on seven screens and it was 200 feet across.
كان على سبع شاشات عبر 200 قدم.
And it was at the height of the Cold War.
وكان في قمة الحرب الباردة.
The Nixon-Khrushchev Kitchen Debate
مناظرة نيكسون - كروشتشيف
happened about 50 feet from where this was shown.
حدثت حوالي 50 قدم من مكان عرض هذا.
And yet, how did it start?
وبعد، كيف بدأ؟
You know, commonality, the first line
انتم تعرفون، القواسم المشتركة، الخط الأول
in Charles' narration was,
في رواية تشارلز كان،
"The same stars that shine down on Russia
" نفس النجوم التي تشع على روسيا
shine down on the United States. From the sky,
تشع على الولايات المتحدة. من السماء,
our cities look much the same."
مدننا تبدو متشابهة جدا."
It was that human connection that Charles and Ray always found in everything.
كان الرابط الانساني هو ما وجده تشارلز وراي في كل شيئ.
And you can imagine, and the thing about it is,
وبامكانك التخيل، والشيء عن ذلك هو،
that they believed that the human mind could handle this number of images
أنهم آمنوا أن العقل الانساني بامكانه تحمل هذا العدد من الصور
because the important thing was to get the gestalt
لأن الشيئ المهم هو الحصول على الشكل الكامل
of what the images were about.
لما كانت عنه هذه الصور.
So that was just a little snip.
لذا كان هذا مجرد قصاصة صغيرة.
But the thing about Charles and Ray
لكن الشيئ عن تشارلز وراي
is that they were always modeling stuff.
أنهم كانوا دائما يجسّمون أشياء.
They were always trying things out.
كانوا دائما يحاولون.
I think one of the things I am passionate about, my grandparents work,
أعتقد أن واحدا من الأشياء التي أنا شغوف بها: عمل جدّاي.
I'm passionate about my work,
أنا شغوف بعملي.
but on top of all that I'm passionate
لكن على رأس كل هذا أنا شغوف
about a holistic vision of design,
بنظرة كليّة للتصميم،
where design is a life skill, not a professional skill.
حيث التصميم مهارة للحياة، ليس مهارة احتراف.
And you know, those of us with kids often want our kids to take music.
وأنتم تعرفون، من لديه اطفال يريداطفاله أن يأخذوا دروس الموسيقى.
I'm no exception.
أنا لست استثناء.
But it's not about them becoming Bono or Tracy Chapman.
لكنه ليس أنهم سيصبحوا بونو أو ترايسي تشابمان.
It's about getting that music thing going through their heads and their thinking.
انه عن أخذ هذه الموسيقى الى عقولهم وتفكيرهم.
Design is the same way. Design has to become that same way.
التصميم هو نفس الشيئ. التصميم عليه أن يصبح نفس الشيئ.
And this is a model that they did of that seven-screen presentation.
وهذا مجسم عملوه لعرض السبع شاشات ذلك.
And Charles just checking it out there.
وتشارلز يتفحصها هنا
So now we're going to go through that door of furniture.
اذن الآن نحن ذاهبون خلال باب الاثاث
This is an unusual installation of airport seating.
هذا تثبيت غير عادي لمقاعد المطار.
So what we're going to see is some of the icons of Eames furniture.
اذن نحن ذاهبون لرؤية بعض الرموز من أثاث ايمز.
And the thing about their furniture is that they said the role of the designer
والشيء عن أثاثهم هو أنهم قالوا ان دور المصمم
was essentially that of a good host,
كان في الأساس من مضيف جيد،
anticipating the needs of the guest.
توقع احتياجات الضيف.
So those are cool images. But these are ones I think are really cool.
اذن تلك صور رائعة و لكن هذه هي التي اعتقد انها رائعة جدا
These are all the prototypes. These are the mistakes,
هذه كلها نماذج اولية. هذه هي الأخطاء.
although I don't think mistakes is the right word in design.
على الرغم من أنني لا أعتقد أن الأخطاء هي الكلمة الصحيحة في التصميم.
It's just the things you try out
انها فقط الأشياء التي تجربها
to kind of make it work better.
لجعلها تعمل افضل بنوع ما
And you know some of them would probably be terrible chairs.
وأنت تعرف بعضهم ربما يكون كراسي سيئة.
Some of them are kind of cool looking. It's like "Hey, why didn't they try that?"
بعضها رائعة الى حد ما. انها مثل "مهلا ، لماذا لم تحاول ذلك؟"
It was that hands-on iterative process
وكان هذا التدريب العملي لعملية تكرارية
which is so much like vernacular design
وهو كثيرا مثل تصميم العامية
and folk design in traditional cultures.
والتصميم الشعبي في الثقافات التقليدية.
And I think that's one of the commonalities between modernism
وأعتقد أن واحدة من القواسم المشتركة بين الحداثة
and traditional design. I think it may be a real common ground
و التصميم التقليدي . أعتقد أنه قد يكون هناك أرضية مشتركة حقيقية
as we kind of figure out what on earth to do in the next 20 or 30 years.
ونحن نحاول معرفة ما يجب القيام به في السنوات ال 20 أو ال 30 المقبلة.
The other thing that's kind of cool is that
والشيء الآخر الرائع في هذا
you look at this and in the media when people say design,
انكم تنظرون الى هذا و في وسائل الإعلام عندما يقول الناس تصميم ،
they actually mean style.
انهم يعنون في الواقع النمط.
And I'm really here to talk about design.
وأنا حقا هنا للحديث عن التصميم.
But you know the object is just a pivot.
لكنكم تعلمون ان الموضوع هو مجرد محوري.
It's a pivot between a process and a system.
انها محور بين عملية ونظام.
And this is a little film I made
وهذا فيلم صغير عملته
about the making of the Eames lounge chair.
حول صناعة كرسي ردهة ايمز
The design process for Charles and Ray
عملية التصميم لتشارلز وراي
never ended in manufacturing.
لم تنتهي ابدا في التصنيع.
It continued. They were always trying to make thing better and better.
انها استمرت. كانوا يحاولون دائما لجعل الاشياء أفضل وأفضل.
Because it's like as Bill Clinton was saying about Rwandan health clinics.
لأنه مثلما كما كان يقول بيل كلينتون عن العيادات الصحية الرواندية.
It's not enough to create one.
انه ليس كافيا عمل واحدة.
You've got to create a system that will work better and better.
عليك إنشاء نظام من شأنه أن يعمل على نحو أفضل وأفضل.
So I've always liked this prototype picture.
اذن لقد أحببت دائما هذه الصورة الاولية.
Because it just kind of, you know, doesn't get any more basic than that.
لأنه كما تعلمون لا يصبح اكثر بساطة من هذا
You try things out.
انت تجرب الاشياء
This is a relatively famous chair.
هذا كرسي شهير نسبيا
Its early version had an "X" base. That's what the collectors like.
انها نسخة مبكرة كان لديها قاعدة على شكل X ,هذا ما احبه الجامعون
Charles and Ray liked this one because it was better.
شارلز وراي احبا هذا لانه كان افضل
It worked better: "H" base, much more practical.
عمل افضل. قاعدة على شكل H كانت عملية اكثر
This is something called a splint.
هذا شيء اسمه(جبيرة)
And I was very touched by Dean Kamen's
و انا تأثرت جدا بعمل دين كامين
work for the military, or for the soldiers,
للجيش,او للجنود
because Charles and Ray designed a molded plywood splint. This is it.
لان تشارلز و راي صمما جبيرة من الخشب الرقائقي المصبوب,هذه هي
And they'd been working on furniture before.
و كانو قد عملو على اثاث من قبل
But doing these splints they learned a lot about the manufacturing process,
لكن عمل هذه الجبائر تعلمو الكثير عن عملية التصنيع
which was incredibly important to them.
الذي كان مهما جدا بالنسبة لهم
I'm trying to show you too much,
انا احاول ان اريكم كثيرا جدا
because I want you to really get a broth of ideas and images.
لاني اريد حقا ان تحصلو على خلاصة الافكار و الصور
This is a house that Charles and Ray designed.
هذا منزل صممه شارلز و راي
My sister is chasing someone else. It's not me.
اختي تلاحق شخصا اخر ليس انا
Although I endorse heartily the fact that he stole her diary, it's not me.
على الرغم من أن أؤيد بشدة واقع أنه سرق مذكراتها، انه ليس انا.
And then this is a film, on the lower left, that Charles and Ray made.
و عندها هذا فيلم الى اليسار في الاسفل عمله شارلز و راي
Now look at that plastic chair.
الان انظرو الى كرسي البلاستيك ذاك
The house is 1949.
المنزل 1949
The chair is done in 1949.
الكرسي كان انتهى في 1949
Charles and Ray,
شارلز وراي
they didn't obsess about style for it's own sake.
فإنهم لم يستحوذو حول أسلوب لذاته.
They didn't say, "Our style is curves. Let's make the house curvy."
لم يقولو"اسلوبنا المنحنيات لنجعل المنزل منحني"
They didn't say, "Our style is grids. Let's make the chair griddy."
لم يقولو"اسلوبنا الشبكات لنجعل المنزل شبكي"
They focused on the need.
انهم ركزو على الحاجة
They tried to solve the design problem.
حاولو حل مشكلة التصميم
Charles used to say, "The extent to which you have a design style
شارلز اعتاد ان يقول:" الغريزة التي لديك لها اسلوب تصميم
is the extent to which you have not solved the design problem."
هي الغريزة التي لم تحل مشكلة التصميم لها"
It's kind of a brutal quote.
انها نوع من اقتباس وحشي
This is the earlier design of that house.
هذا هو التصميم الاولي لذلك المنزل
And again, they managed to figure out a way to make a prototype
و مجددا استطاعو ايجاد طريقة لعمل نموذج اولي
of a house -- architecture, very expensive medium.
لمنزل ,معماري ,وسط باهظ جدا
Here's a film we've been hearing things about.
هذا فيلم كنا نسمع اشياء عنه
The "Powers of Ten" is a film they made.
(قوة العشرة) هو فيلم عملوه
If we watch the next clip,
لو شاهدنا المقطع التالي
you're going to see the first version of "Powers of Ten," upper left.
سترون النسخة الاولى من (قوة العشرة) اليسار العلوي
The familiar one on the lower right.
والذي تعرفونه في اسفل اليمين
The Eames' film Tops, lower left.
يتصدر فيلم ايمز ، اسفل اليسار.
And a lamp that Charles designed for a church.
و مصباح صممه شارلز لكنيسة
Video: Which in turn belongs to a local group of galaxies.
فيديو : ما هو بدوره ينتمي إلى مجموعة محلية من المجرات.
These form part of a grouping system
كانت تشكل جزءا من نظام تجمعات
much as the stars do.
بقدر ما تفعل النجوم.
They are so many and so varied that from this distance
فهي كثيرة جدا ومتنوعة جدا من هذه المسافة
they appear like the stars from Earth.
تظهر مثل النجوم من الأرض.
ED: You've seen that film, and what's so great about this
كنتم قد رأيتم هذا الفيلم ، وما هو رائع جدا في هذا
whole conference is that everybody has been talking about scale.
المؤتمر كله هو أن الجميع كان يتحدث عن النطاق.
Everybody here is coming at it from a different way.
الجميع هنا يأتي اليها من طريقة مختلفة.
I want to give you one example.
أريد أن أعطي لكم مثالا واحدا.
E.O. Wilson once told me that when he looked at ants --
ويلسون قال لي ذات مرة انه عندما نظر إلى النمل --
he loved them, of course, and he wanted to learn more about them --
كان عاشقا لها ، طبعا، وانه يريد معرفة المزيد عنها --
he consciously looked at them from the standpoint of scale.
وقال انه يتطلع بوعي عليهم من وجهة نظر الحجم.
So here is the tiny creature.
اذن هنا هذا المخلوق الصغير.
And yet simply by changing the frame of reference
وببساطة بتغيير الإطار المرجعي
it reveals so much, including what ended up being the TED Prize.
انه يكشف الكثير ، بما في ذلك ما انتهى بجائزة تيد(TED Prize).
Modeling, they tried modeling all the time. They were always modeling things.
النمذجة ، حاولوا النمذجة في كل وقت. وكانوا دائما يضعون الأشياء في نماذج
And I think part of that is that they never delegated understanding.
وأعتقد أن جزءا من ذلك هو أنها لم تفوض التفاهم.
And I think in our family we were very lucky,
وأعتقد أننا في عائلتنا كنا محظوظين للغاية.
because we learned about design backwards.
لأن تعلمنا عن التصميم الى الخلف.
Design was not something other.
لم يكن التصميم شيء آخر.
It was part of the business of life in general.
كان جزء من أعمال الحياة بصفة عامة.
It was part of the quality of life.
وكان جزء من نوعية الحياة.
And here is some family pictures.
وهنا بعض الصور العائلية.
And you can see why I'm down on style, with a haircut like that.
ويمكنك ان ترى لماذا أنا باستمرار على نمط ، مع شعر من هذا القبيل.
But anyway, (Laughter)
لكن على أي حال ، (ضحك)
I remember the cut grapefruit that we would have at the Eames house when I was a kid.
أتذكر قصَة الجريب فروت في بيت ايمز عندما كنت طفلا.
So we're going to watch another film.
اذن نحن ذاهبون لمشاهدة فيلم آخر.
This is a film, the one called Toys.
هذا الفيلم ، المسمى(الدُمى).
You can see me, I have the same haircut, in the upper right corner.
يمكنك ان تراني ، ولدي قصة الشعر نفسها ، في الزاوية اليمنى العليا.
Upper left is a film they did on toy trains.
اليسار العلوي هو فيلم عملوه على دُمى القطارات.
Lower right is a solar do-nothing toy.
اسفل اليمين هي لعبة شمسية لا تفعل شيئا .
Lower left is Day-of-the-Dead toys.
أسفل اليسار هو لعبة يوم الموتى.
Charles used to say that toys are not as innocent as they appear.
اعتاد تشارلز القول بأن اللعب ليس بريئة كما تبدو.
They are often the precursor to bigger things.
فإنها غالبا ما تكون مقدمة لأشياء أكبر.
And these ideas -- that train up there, being about the honest use of materials,
وهذه الأفكار -- ذلك القطار هناك ، يجري حول الاستخدام الصادق للمواد ،
is totally the same
هو تماما نفس
as the honest use of materials in the plywood.
كاستخدام المواد الصادق في الخشب الرقائقي.
And now I'm going to test you.
والآن انا ساختبركم
This is a letter that my grandfather sent to my mom when she was five years old.
هذه هي رسالة بعث بها جدي لأمي عندما كان عمرها خمس سنوات.
So can you read it?
اذن هل تستطيعون قرائتها؟
Lucia angel,
ملاكي لوسيا ،
okay, eye.
حسنا ، العين.
Audience: Saw many trains.
الجمهور : لقد رأى العديد من القطارات.
ED: Awl, also, good that the leather crafter's guild is here.
الخرامه ، أيضا ، وحسن أن نقابة فنان الجلد هو هنا.
Also, what is he doing? Row, rowed.
أيضا ، ماذا يفعل؟ جذف الخلاف.
Sun? No. Well is there another name for a sunrise?
الشمس؟ لا حسنا هل هناك اسم آخر لشروق الشمس؟
Dawn, very good.
الفجر ، جيدة جدا.
Also rode on one. I ...
ركب أيضا على واحد. أنا...
Audience: You had, I hope you had --
الجمهور : كان لديك ، وأنا آمل أن تكونوا قد --
ED: Now you've been to the website Dogs of Saint Louis
والآن كنت قد تم على موقع كلاب سانت لويس
in the late, in the mid-1930's,
في وقت متأخر ، في منتصف عام 1930 ،
then you'd know that was a Great Dane.
ثم كنت أعرف أنه كان دانماركي العظيم.
So, I hope you had a
لذا ، فإنني آمل أن تكونوا قد
Audience: Nice time, time --
الجمهور : وقت جميل، وقت --
ED: Time at.
وقت في
Citizen Kane, rose --
وردة, المواطن كين ، --
Audience: Rosebud.
الجمهور : البرعم.
ED: No, bud. "D"'s right. At Buddy's --
لا ، برعم. "دال" صحيح. في الأصدقاء و--
Audience: Party. Love.
الجمهور : حفلة. حب.
ED: Okay, good.
حسنا ، جيد.
So, "I saw many trains and also rode on one.
بذلك ، وقال "رأيت العديد من القطارات وركبت أيضا على واحد.
I hope you had a nice time at Buddy's party."
آمل أن تكوني قد قضيتي وقتا طيبا في حفلة الأصدقاء ".
So you guys did pretty good, cool.
وكذلك انتم يا رفاق اديتم جيدا ، رائع.
So my mom and Charles had this great relationship
اذن كان لامي و تشارلز هذه العلاقة الرائعة
where they'd send those sorts of things back and forth to one another.
حيث انهم كانو يرسلون هذا النوع من الاشياء الى بعضهم البعض.
And it's all part of the, you know,
والأمر كله جزء من ، كما تعلمون ،
they used to say, "Take your pleasure seriously."
كانوا يقولون : "خذ متعتك على محمل الجد".
These are some images from a project of mine
هذه هي بعض الصور من مشروع لي
that's called Kymaerica.
يسمى (كايمايريكا)
It's sort of an alternative universe.
انه نوع من عالم بديل.
It's kind of a reinterpretation of the landscape.
انها نوع من إعادة تفسير للمناظر الطبيعية.
Those plaques are plaques we've been installing around North America.
تلك اللوحات هي لوحات كنا نركبها في مختلف أنحاء أميركا الشمالية.
We're about to do six in the U.K. next week.
نحن على وشك القيام بستة في المملكة المتحدة. الاسبوع المقبل.
And they honor events in the linear world from the fictional world.
وهي تكريم في العالم الحقيقي لاحداث في العالم الخيالي
So, of course, since it's bronze it has to be true.
ذلك ، بالطبع ، لأنه من البرونز عليه أن يكون صحيحا.
Video: Kymaerica with waterfalls,
الفيديو : كايمايريكا مع الشلالات ،
tumbling through our --
هبوط من خلال موقعنا --
ED: This is one of the traditional Kymaerican songs.
وهذه واحدة من الأغاني الكايمايريكية التقليدية.
And so we had spelling bees in Paris, Illinois.
و هكذا كنا نملي كلمة (نحل) في باريس الينوي
Video: Your word is N. Carolina.
الفيديو : الكلمة هي ن. كارولينا.
Girl: Y-I-N-D-I-A-N-A.
الفتاة : أنا ص ن مد من أ إلى ط ن أ.
ED: And then Embassy Row is actually a historical site,
وبعد ذلك صف السفارة هو في الواقع موقع التاريخي.
because in the Kymaerican story
لأن في القصة الكايمايريكية
this is where the Parisian Diaspora started, where there embassy was.
هذا هو المكان الذي بدأ فيه الشتات الباريسي ، حيث كانت توجد السفارة.
So you can actually visit and have this three-dimensional
حتى تتمكن من زيارة هذا في الواقع ثلاثي الأبعاد
fictional experience there.
تجربة خيالية هناك.
And the town has really embraced it.
والمدينة احتضنتها حقا.
We had the spelling bee in conjunction with the Gwomeus Club.
كان لدينا النحل الإملائي بالتعاون مع نادي جوميوس.
But what is really cool is that we take our visual environment
ولكن ما هو حقا رائع هو ان نأخذ بيئتنا البصرية
as inevitable. And it's not.
كما لا مفر منها. وانها ليست كذلك.
Other things could have happened. The Japanese could have discovered Monterey.
يمكن لاشياء اخرى ان تكون حدثت. قد يكون اكتشف اليابانيين مونتيري.
And we could have been born 100,000 years ago.
وكان من الممكن أن نولد نحن قبل 100000 سنة مضت.
And there are a lot of fun things. This is the Museum of the Bench.
وهناك الكثير من الاشياء الممتعة. هذا هو متحف مقاعد البدلاء.
They have trading cards
لديهم بطاقات تجارية.
and all sorts of cool things.
وجميع أنواع الأشياء الرائعة.
And you're kind of trapped in the texture of Kymaerica.
وانت كنوع من المحاصرين في نسيج كايمايريكا.
The Tahatchabe, the great road building culture.
و التاهاتشيب ،ثقافة بناء الطرق الرائعة.
A guy named Nobu Naga,
رجل اسمه نوبو ناجا ،
the so-called Japanese Columbus.
ما يسمى بكولومبس الياباني .
But now I'm going to return you to the real world.
ولكن الآن انا عائد بكم الى العالم الحقيقي.
And this is Cranbrook. I've got a real treat for you,
وهذه هي كرانبروك. لدي هدية رائعة لكم .
which is the first film that Charles ever made.
التي هي اول فلم عمله تشارلز
So let's watch that. Nobody's ever seen it.
اذن دعونا نشاهد ذاك. لم يره احد من قبل ابدا
Cranbrook is very generous to let us show it for the first time here.
كرانبوك كانو كريمين جدا ليدعونا نعرض هذا لأول مرة هنا
It's a film about Maya Gretel, a famous ceramicist, and a teacher at Cranbrook.
انه فلم عن مايا غريتيل ,صانعة خزف مشهورة,و معلمة في كرانبوك
And he made it for the 1939 faculty exhibition.
و عمله لمعرض الكلية العام 1939
Silent. We don't have a track for it yet.
صمت. ليس لدينا مسار له بعد
Very simple. It's just a start. But it's that learn-by-doing thing.
بسيط للغاية.انه فقط بداية.لكنه التعلم عن طريق عمل الشيء
You want to learn how to make films? Go make a movie.
اتريد ان تتعلم كيفية صناعة الافلام؟ اصنع فلم
And you try something out.
و تجرب شيء ما
But here is what's really great.
لكن هنا ما هو رائع حقا
See that chair there? The orange one? That's the organic chair. 1940.
اترون الكرسي هناك؟الكرسي البرتقالي؟انه الكرسي العضوي 1940
At the same time that Charles was doing that chair,
في نفس الوقت الذي كان تشارلز يصنع ذاك الكرسي
he was doing this film.
كان يصنع هذا الفلم
So my point is that this scope of vision, this holistic vision
اذن وجهة نظري هي أن هذا المجال من الرؤية ،هذه الرؤية الشمولية
of design, was with them from the beginning.
للتصميم كانت معهم من البداية
It wasn't like "Oh, we made some chairs and got successful.
لم يكن مثل"آه لقد صنعنا بعض الكراسي و نجحنا"
Now we're going to do some movies."
الان سنصنع بعض الافلام"
It was always part of how they looked at the world. And that's what's really powerful.
لقد كان دائما جزء من كيفية نظرهم للعالم.و هذا ما كان قويا حقا
And I think that all of us in this room, as you move design forward,
و انا اعتقد اننا كلنا في هذ الغرفة و انتم تحركون التصميم الى الامام
it's not about just doing one thing.
انه ليس فقط عن عمل شيء واحد
It's about how you approach problems. And there is this huge, beautiful commonality
انه عن كيفية اقترابك من المشاكل وهنالك هذه القواسم المشتركة الكبيرة و الجميلة
between design, business and the world.
بين التصميم و الاعمال و العالم
So we're going to do the last clip.
اذن سنعرض آخر مقطع
And I've shown you some of the images. I just want to focus on sound now.
و قد اريتكم بعض الصور اريد فقط ان نركز على الصوت الان
So this is Charles' voice.
اذن هذا هو صوت تشارلي
Charles Eames: In India, those without, and the lowest in caste,
تشارلز ايمز: في الهند ,اولئك الذين لا يملكون,و ادنى في المجتمع
eat very often, particularly in southern India,
يأكلون,في كثير من الاحيان ,ولا سيما في جنوب الهند
they eat off of a banana leaf.
يأكلون على ورق الموز
And those a little bit up the scale
و اولئك الذين اعلى قليلا
eat off of a sort of a low-fired ceramic dish.
يأكلون من اطباق خزفية رديئة
And a little bit higher, why they have a glaze
و اعلى قليلا ,لماذا لديهم طلاء
on a thing they call a thali.
على شيئ يسمى (سالي)
If you're up the scale a little bit more,
اذا كنت في نطاق اعلى قليلا
why, a brass thali.
لماذا سالي من النحاس
And then things get to be a little questionable.
و بعد ذلك الاشياء تصبح اكثر قليلا اثارة للتساؤل
There are things like silver-plated thalis.
انها اشياء مثل سالي مطلي بالفضة
And there is solid silver thalis.
و هنالك سالي من الفضة
And I suppose some nut has had a
و انا افترض ان مجنون ما كان لديه
gold thali that he's eaten off of.
سالي من الذهب ليأكل منه
But you can go beyond that.
لكن تستطيع الذهاب ابعد من ذاك
And the guys that have not only means,
و الرجال الذين لديهم ليس فقط وسائل
but a certain amount of knowledge and understanding,
لكن مقدار معين من الفهم و المعرفة
go to the next step, and they eat off a banana leaf.
يذهبون الى الخطوة التالية,و يأكلون من ورقة موز
And I think that in these times
وانا اعتقد انه في هذه الاوقات
when we fall back and regroup,
عندما نتراجع و نتجمع
that somehow or other,
انه بطريقة او بأخرى
the banana leaf parable
ورقة الموز
sort of got to get working there,
تنفع بشكل ما هناك.
because I'm not prepared to say
لاني لست مستعد لأقول
that the banana leaf that one eats off of
ان ورقة التي يأكل منها الفرد
is the same as the other eats off of.
هي مثلها مثل التي يأكل منها الاخرين
But it is that process that has happened within the man
لكن ذلك هو أن العملية التي حدثت داخل الرجل،
that changes the banana leaf.
هي التي تغير ورقة الموز
ED: I've been looking forward to sharing that quote with you.
أ د:لقدد كنت اتطلع الى مشاركة هذا الاقتباس معكم
Because that's part of where we've got to get to.
لان ذلك جزء من حيث يجب علينا الوصول
And I also want to share this one.
و اريد ايضا مشاركة هذه
"Beyond the age of information is the age of choices."
"ما وراء عصر المعلومات هو عصر من الخيارات."
And I really think that's where we are.
و انا اعتقد حقا ان هذا ما نحن فيه
And it's kind of cool for me to be part of a family
و من الرائع لي ان اكون جزء من عائلة
and a tradition where he was talking about that in 1978.
وتقليد حيث كان يتحدث عن ذلك في 1978.
And part of why this stuff is important
و جزء من لماذا هذه الاشياء مهمة
and all the things that we do are important,
و كل الاشياء التي نفعلها مهمة
is that these are the ideas we need.
غير أن هذه هي الأفكار التي نحتاج إليها.
And I think that this is all part of surrendering to the design journey.
وأعتقد أن هذا كله جزء من الاستسلام لرحلة التصميم.
That's what we all need to do.
هذا كل ما نحتاج لفعله
Design is not just for designers anymore. It's a process. It's not style.
التصميم ليس للمصممي فقط بعد الآن. انها عملية. انه ليس اسلوب.
All that great thinking needs to really get about solving
كل ذلك يحتاج إلى تفكير كبير حقا الحصول على معلومات عن حل
pretty key problems.
المشاكل الرئيسية
I really thank you for your time.
حقا أشكر لكم وقتكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)